nextiva.com 2018-10-22

# PRIVACY

PRIVACY
       POLICY
   (800) 285-7995
 Nextiva.com/Support

                                          Nextiva® Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy identiﬁes and describes the way Nextiva, Inc. (“Nextiva”) uses and protects the
information we collect about Customers and Users. All uses of Nextiva’s products and services, as well
as visits to our websites, are subject to this Privacy Policy. This Policy applies to all Customers and
Users. The Customer who holds the account with Nextiva is responsible for making sure all family
members or other Users under the same account understand and agree to this Policy. Information that
you provide to non-Nextiva companies is not covered by this Policy and Nextiva shall have no
responsibility for protecting any such information divulged by Customer/User to a non-Nextiva
company.
As used in this Policy, the terms listed below have the following meanings:
Customer - A "Customer" is anyone who purchases Nextiva products or services. When a Customer
purchases retail products or services for use by others, those individuals also may be considered
Customers for purposes of this Policy.
User - A "User" is anyone who visits our websites.
Personal Information - "Personal Information" is information that directly identiﬁes or reasonably can
be used to identify an individual Customer or User. Examples include name, address, telephone
number, e-mail address, Social Security number, and ﬁnancial account number. Personal Information
does not include Published Listing Information as discussed in more detail below or information that is
readily available to the public through no fault of Nextiva.
Anonymous Information - "Anonymous Information" means information that does not directly identify
and cannot reasonably be used to identify an individual Customer or User.
Aggregate Information - "Aggregate Information" means information about groups or categories of
Customers or Users, which does not identify and cannot reasonably be used to identify an individual
Customer or User. Aggregate Information is a kind of Anonymous Information.
Website - "Website" means any page or location on the Internet, no matter what device (cell phone,
lap top, PC, etc.) or protocol (http, WAP, ftp or other) is used to access the page or location. In this
Policy, we use the term website other similar terms such as "Internet site," "site," and "web page."
1. Information - We may collect diﬀerent types of personal and other information based on your use
of our products and services and our business relationship with you, including contact information;
billing information, equipment, performance, Nextiva’s website usage, viewing and other technical
information about your use of our network, services, products or websites. Information may be
collected when you give it to us with the intent to purchase or interact with us about a product or
service we oﬀer or provide; when we collect it automatically when you visit our websites or use our
products and services; or when we obtain it from other sources, such as credit agencies. Our goal of
collecting your information is to provide you with the best customer experience possible by
communicating with you regarding service updates, oﬀers and promotions; delivering advertising that
                                                                                             © 2016 NEXTIVA, ALL RIGHTS RESERVED

may be of interest to you; addressing network and security issues; investigating or taking action
regarding illegal activities or violations of our Terms of Service or Acceptable Use Policies.
We collect some information on an anonymous basis and may anonymize the personal information we
collect about you into data groups. When we employ non-Nextiva companies to anonymize or
aggregate data on our behalf, the requirements for sharing Personal Information with non-companies
apply. We may share aggregate or anonymous information in various formats with trusted non-Nextiva
entities, with whom we have contracted with to aggregate such data and may work with those entities
to do research and provide products and services. When Nextiva jointly provides a service with a non-
Nextiva company, your Personal Information may be subject to both this Policy and the privacy policy
of the non- Nextiva company. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any non- Nextiva
company with which you do business to determine what information will be collected and how it will
be used or disclosed to others.
2. Disclosure - We do not sell your Personal Information to anyone for any purpose, and we maintain
information about you in our business records while you are a customer, or until it is no longer needed
for business, tax, or legal purposes. We have implemented encryption or other appropriate security
controls to protect Personal Information when stored or transmitted by Nextiva.
Subject to applicable legal restrictions, such as those that exist for CPNI (as deﬁned below), the Nextiva
family of companies may share your Personal Information with each other to make sure your
experience is as seamless as possible, and you have the full beneﬁt of what Nextiva and its subsidiaries
have to oﬀer.
We share your Personal Information only with non-Nextiva companies that perform services on our
behalf, and only as necessary for them to perform those services. We require those non-Nextiva
companies to protect any Personal Information they may receive in a manner consistent with this
policy, and we do not provide Personal Information to non-Nextiva companies for the marketing of
their own products and services without your consent. We may provide Personal Information to
non-Nextiva companies or other third parties for purposes such as emergencies, pursuant to court
orders, compliance with the law or a lawful government, judicial, administrative, or law enforcement
request (i.e. search warrant, subpoena, court order, discovery request), identity veriﬁcation to prevent
fraud and identity theft, enforcing of property rights, or obtaining payment for products and services
that appear on your Nextiva billing statements.
3. Customer Proprietary Network Information. Customer Proprietary Network Information (CPNI) is
information that Nextiva obtains when providing your telecommunications services to you. CPNI
includes the types of telecommunications services you purchased, how you use the services, and the
billing information related to those services, including items such as the types of telecommunications
services that you have purchased and your calling details. Your telephone number, name and address
are not considered CPNI.
We use your CPNI to oﬀer you additional services of the type you already purchase from Nextiva. We
also may use your CPNI to oﬀer you products and services, packages, discounts and promotions from
Nextiva and its aﬃliates, such as fax service, analytic tools and other uniﬁed communication tools,
                                                                                          © 2016 NEXTIVA, ALL RIGHTS RESERVED

which may be diﬀerent from the types of services you already purchase. Nextiva has strict policy
guidelines to safeguard the privacy of CPNI and protect it from unauthorized access or improper use.
Nextiva does not sell, trade, or otherwise share your CPNI with anyone outside of Nextiva or its
aﬃliated companies or with anyone who is not authorized to represent us to oﬀer our services or to
perform functions on our behalf, except as the law may require or you may authorize.
In order to opt-out and restrict access to your CPNI for our own marketing purposes, please contact us
within 30 days of this notice by clicking the following link or going to the following website
http://go.nextiva.com/emailPreference/e/64132/100. If you do not notify us within 30 days of this
notiﬁcation that you wish to restrict our use of your CPNI, we will assume that you approve of our use
of CPNI for this purpose.
4. Privacy Controls - You can review and correct your Personal Information collected by us. You can
limit certain types of solicitation communications from Nextiva, including marketing contacts made via
telephone, e-mail and text messaging by notifying Nextiva. We will provide you with notice of changes
to this policy. We are happy to correct information found to be inaccurate. Customers may verify that
appropriate corrections have been made.
5. Internet-based Advertising – Nextiva uses cookies to store information that can be used to serve
ads relevant to your interests, and to help our advertisers measure the eﬀectiveness of a particular
advertisement. This helps us tailor ads to your interests. These cookies can not only help us ensure
that you do not repeatedly see the same ads, but (if you opt-out) they can also help us prevent you
from seeing targeted ads at all. The information collected with these cookies is not
personally-identiﬁable, and we do not associate it with your Personal Information.
You may opt out of Nextiva’s use of data for internet-based advertising. Please keep in mind that even
after you opt-out, you may still continue to see ads, but they will no longer be tailored to your
interests.
Opting-out also does not remove Nextiva cookies. They will remain on your computer, but we will not
use the data connected to your cookie for our services. Please note that if you delete your cookies,
you will need to opt-out again to avoid being served targeted ads in the future. Users can control the
use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your
ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.
To opt out of the beneﬁts of our targeted ads, click here: Disable Nextiva Cookie
We have relationships with other third party advertising companies to place advertisements on this
website and other websites, and to perform tracking and reporting functions for this website and other
websites. These third party advertising companies may place cookies on your computer when you visit
our website or other websites so that they can display targeted advertisements to you. These third
party advertising companies do not collect Personal Information in this process, and we do not give
any Personal Information to them. However, this Privacy Statement does not cover the collection
methods or use of the information collected by these entities. For more information about third party
advertising, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI). Opt out of being targeted by many
                                                                                          © 2016 NEXTIVA, ALL RIGHTS RESERVED

third party advertising companies by visiting NAI's Consumer Opt-Out orTRUSTe's Opt-Out.
6. Exclusions - Information that you provide to non-Nextiva companies is not covered by this Policy.
For example: When you download applications or make an online purchase from a non-Nextiva
company while using Nextiva’s services, the information collected by the non-Nextiva company is not
subject to this Policy. If you use public forums — such as social networking services, Internet bulletin
boards, chat rooms, or blogs on Nextiva or non-Nextiva websites — you should be aware that any
Personal Information you disclose publicly can be read, collected, or used by others. Once you choose
to reveal Personal Information on such a site, the information is publicly available, and Nextiva cannot
prevent distribution and use of that information by other parties.
Nextiva may enter into written product or service agreements with business customers that contain
speciﬁc provisions related to the conﬁdentiality, security or other handling of information. When
provisions of a written product or service agreement diﬀer from or conﬂict with the provisions of this
Policy, the terms of the written agreement will apply. In all other instances, the terms of this Policy
apply.
7. Security - We have established electronic and administrative safeguards designed to secure the
information we collect, to prevent unauthorized access to or disclosure of that information and to
ensure it is used appropriately. Although we strive to keep your Personal Information secure, no
security measures are absolute, and we cannot guarantee that your Personal Information will never be
disclosed in a manner inconsistent with this Policy (for example, as the result of unauthorized acts by
third parties that violate the law or this Policy). We will make reasonable attempts to notify you if we
determine that Nextiva has experienced a security breach and there is a reasonably likely risk of
identity theft, or where otherwise required by law.
8. Policies - We have established policies and practices to meet the expectations of Customers and
potential customers who have expressed a desire to limit certain types of solicitation communications
from Nextiva, including marketing contacts made via telephone, e-mail and text messaging. You also
can request to be removed from these telemarketing lists when you receive a marketing or
promotional call. Where required by state laws and/or regulations, we honor requests from businesses
to be removed from our telemarketing lists.
The FTC maintains a National Do Not Call Registry at https://www.donotcall.gov/, and your state
may maintain its own Do Not Call Registry. Putting your number on these Registries also may limit our
telemarketing calls to that number.
Our practices as described above are designed to satisfy state and federal legal requirements limiting
marketing contacts. You should know that those laws and regulations — such as the requirements
governing the state and federal "Do Not Call" lists — generally permit companies to contact their own
current and, in some cases, former customers, even when those customers are listed on the federal
and state "Do Not Call" lists. Similarly, restricting our use of your CPNI will not eliminate all types of
Nextiva marketing contacts.
9. Online Advertising - Nextiva works hard to detect and prevent junk e-mails (also referred to as
                                                                                            © 2016 NEXTIVA, ALL RIGHTS RESERVED

"spam" e-mails) from ever reaching your computer. However, if you are receiving unwanted spam from
a Nextiva e-mail address, please contact us for assistance at marketing@nextiva.com.
10. Account Set-Up - When selecting User names and passwords for Nextiva accounts, you should
choose words or characters that are not obvious. Likewise, you should always keep Personal
Information such as account numbers, Usernames, passwords or similar information in a secure place
and not share the information with others.
11. Policy Changes - Information about our Customers and Users, including Personal Information, may
be transferred as part of any merger, acquisition, sale of company assets, or transition of service to
another provider, as well as in the unlikely event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership in which
Customer and User records would be transferred to another entity as a result of such a proceeding.
We reserve the right to update this Privacy Policy as necessary to reﬂect any changes we make and to
satisfy legal requirements. If we make a material change to this Policy, we will post a prominent notice
of the change on our websites, and provide you with other appropriate notice and choice regarding the
use of your information, at least 30 days before the eﬀective date.
Please check our websites periodically for changes to this Privacy Policy.
We are happy to address any questions or concerns you may have about our privacy practices and
policies. You may e-mail us at marketing@nextiva.com or write to us at 8800
E. Chaparral Road, Suite 300; Scottsdale, Arizona, 85250. If you believe you have been aggrieved by
any act of ours in violation of the law, we encourage you to contact us directly at either of these
addresses to resolve your question or issue.
You also have the option of ﬁling a complaint with the FTC Bureau of Consumer Protection, using an
online form, or by calling toll-free 1-877-FTC-HELP (1-877-328-4357; TTY: 1-866- 653- 4261. Other
rights and remedies also may be available to you under federal or other applicable laws.
Updated: September 27, 2016
                                                                                         © 2016 NEXTIVA, ALL RIGHTS RESERVED
